#### **Current Employment:**

# Hill + Knowlton Strategies

http://www.hkstrategies.com/

Senior Font-end Developer

(March 2014 - Present)

Hired as the senior front-end developer at the Global headquarters of Hill + Knowlton Strategies in New York City, Thomas specializes in user interface development for both the internal product team and the digital studio. He has enjoyed building bleeding edge web applications for both clients and the internal practice teams.

The diversity of work has allowed Thomas to keep abreast with the latest web technology stacks while collaborating with a nationally distributed team.

#### **Previous Employment:**

#### TheRedPin.com

http://www.theredpin.com/

Lead User Interface Developer

(August 2012 - March 2013)

At TheRedPin.com Thomas was responsible for crafting the front-end user interface and web application framework. Working closely with designers, back-end developers and product owners, he was able refresh the entire user experience and property mapping capabilities in a short amount of time.

Using BackboneJS and modular MVC patterns Thomas was able to create a robust and future friendly web application that is still in use today. Coordinating through daily scrums with his team members and product manager he was able to consistently improve and refine the site's user experience while adding features to satisfy product owner's requests.

## **Critical Mass**

http://www.criticalmass.com/

Senior Developer

(November 2010-August 2012)

While an employee at Critical Mass, Thomas was responsible for directing globally distributed development teams in the creation and maintenance of high profile commercial web sites. He ensured his team members adhered to accepted web practices while satisfying the widest range of devices.

Thomas enjoyed working in development teams as small as 3 (www.infiniti.com) and as large as 20 members (www.miteam.adidas.com). Daily scrums and design co-ordinations were utilized to keep projects on pace for timely delivery.

Clients Included: Citibank, Adidas, Infiniti Global, and more

#### **CBC**

http://www.cbc.ca/

User Interface Developer

(September 2009-November 2010)

At the CBC, Thomas was responsible for the front-end development and maintenance of a large multimedia publication system. Working with a team of 12, he instituted various coding standards and guidelines across the Canadian Broadcasting Corporation for many of the satellite web teams located around the globe.

Thomas' proudest accomplishments at the CBC were the technical assessment document for the CBC.ca homepage redesign in 2010, as well as the Consolidated Media Portal.

#### henderson bas

http://www.theniceagency.com/

Senior Interface Developer (June 2008 – September 2009)

# Quality Assurance Analyst

(September 2007 -June 2008)

At henderson bas, Thomas was responsible for full cross-browser project testing. All digital deployments were copy checked, and fully tested. He collected all necessary project details for writing test plans while training his eye for detail. Eventually he weaseled his way onto the frontend development team.

Thomas was quickly promoted from QA to front-end developer, to senior front-end developer and eventually became the lead for all front-end deployments for iCoke.com.

Clients Included: Coca-Cola, Nintendo, Molson, Tim Horton's, Joe Fresh, and more

**Example Projects** 

Infiniti Global Redesign

http://www.infiniti.com/

**CBC Radio Player** 

www.cbc.ca/video/radio/popup/

**CBC: the National** 

http://www.cbc.ca/thenational/

Adidas miTeam

http://www.miteam.adidas.com/

Coca cola

www.icoke.ca/

**Molson Canadian Redesign** 

www.molsoncanadian.ca/

**CBC Home Page Redesign** 

http://www.cbc.ca/

Nintendo

http://www.nintendo.ca/

## **Freelance Projects:**

# **Ivey School of Business**

http://www.iveytour.ca/

## Web Developer

Thomas developed the mobile web app for use by visitors to the Ivey Business School. The web app assisted participants in touring and learning more about the school. Thomas was responsible for architecting and building the user interface and motion design, as well as developing the back-end services for the contest form submission and database capture.

## ADIDAS: #BOOST Sign up & Win

http://adidas.theaircraft.co/ipad/

## Web Developer

Thomas developed the iPad installed web app. The web app provided in store sales reps with the ability to provide entrants with an easy and configurable contest registration form in store.

#### **ADIDAS: Scan shoes & Win**

http://www.scanshoesandwin.com/

## Web Developer

Thomas developed the front and back-end architecture for the Scan Shoes & Win promotion by Adidas. Users scanned a QR code that sent their mobile browser to a contest sign up page that would return a randomly assigned prize code and an automated email response. Included full form validation and Google Maps API integration.

#### Savannah

http://www.savannah-shop.com/ (No longer available)

#### Web Developer

With his partner, Thomas created an online retail business. Thomas designed and built the entire front-end theme leveraging Shopify's hosted ecommerce platform. The website was developed with "mobile first" in mind and is fully responsive. Thomas has become a very competent Shopify theme developer, fluent with the liquid templating system

#### **Education:**

## **York University**

Bachelor of Arts: Information Technology

Thomas completed a four-year study of Information Technology. Courses included computer science, network architecture, user interface design, web development, database development, human and computer interaction, mathematics, computer algorithm analysis, and social studies.

# **Skills Sets**

Technical	Aesthetic	Architecture
• JavaScript	Wireframing	<ul> <li>Interaction Design</li> </ul>
• CoffeeScript	User Interface Design	Design Patterns
• HTML5 + CSS3	• Product Sketches	• Information architecture
• Rapid Prototyping	Mobile Design	• User Interface Design
• Responsive Layouts	• Form Design	Wire framing
• Code Documentation	<ul><li>Photoshop</li></ul>	• User Testing
	• Illustration	
	• Doodling	

Libraries and Frameworks	Server-side	<b>Build tools</b>
• jQuery	• Express JS	• Grunt JS
Backbone JS	<ul><li>MongoDB</li></ul>	• Gulp JS
<ul><li>Angular JS</li></ul>	• Hapi JS	Preprocessors
• React JS	• PHP	• SASS + LESS
• Require JS	• SQL	<ul> <li>CoffeeScript</li> </ul>
<ul><li>Browserify</li></ul>		<ul><li>Compass</li></ul>
<ul> <li>Modernizer</li> </ul>	<b>UI Frameworks</b>	• JSX
<ul> <li>Velocity JS</li> </ul>	<ul><li>Bootstrap</li></ul>	Package Tools
• GSAP	<ul><li>Foundation</li></ul>	• Bower
		• NPM

References and additional project information can be supplied upon request.

Linked In: <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/b/902/bb6">http://www.linkedin.com/pub/b/902/bb6</a>

Website: <a href="http://thomfoolery.github.io">http://thomfoolery.github.io</a>
Email: <a href="mailto:thomas.yuill@gmail.com">thomas.yuill@gmail.com</a>